# Tran Thanh Trong

Senior Software Engineer Thap Muoi, Dong Thap District, Viet Nam (+84) 706641166 trongtt.it@gmail.com

# **SUMMARY**

Beginning my career as a Java developer since 2019, within that time I have worked across technologies and business domains. While working across the Java technology stacks I have experienced in developing applications using Spring modules and front-end Javascripts frameworks like React. I am a quick and continuous learner, I have always wanted to improve myself through learning online courses and any possible way.

# **EXPERIENCE**

FPT Software - Senior Software Engineer

Highlights projects:

Jan 2020 - April 2020 & Feb 2021 - present

- On-going project: **Workbench**, *Web-based application* Feb 2021 - **present** 
  - *Description:* An application portal for employees landing page.
  - *Technologies:* A Java Spring Boot web-based application that handles Oracle SAML. Later, we migrated the apps to Okta OIDC SSO. Besides, I am also participating in troubleshooting large scale system issues.
  - Role: Key Member.
- Past Project: **Message Gateway,** *Web-based application* Jan 2020 - April 2020
  - Description: Application portal for Email template management. The system creates Email templates for later message users on business events.
  - Technologies: A Java Spring Boot web-based application with Camunda Modeler that design business processes and deploy to trigger Sendgrid email messaging templates.
     Front-end with ReactJS Ant Design.
  - Role: Working as a member.

**Other** - Software Engineer

- Past Project: **IBDFree**, *Web-based application* Oct 2020 - June 2021
  - Description: For enhancing diagnosis Inflammatory bowel disease (shorts IBD), a kind of cancer, we had developed an application and wrote a paper on that subject. Ref: Enhancing Inflammatory Bowel Disease Diagnosis Performance Using Chi-Squared

Algorithm on Metagenomic Data. Springer, Singapore. https://doi.org/10.1007/978-981-19-3394-3\_77.

- *Technologies:* A web-based application that consists of 3 main components: diagnostic analysis APIs with Python Django, Spring Boot role-based for user facing APIs and front-end with ReactJS library Ant Design Pro.
- Role: Working as a team leader.
- Past Project: **Food Fast,** *Android Application*May 2020 Sep 2020
  - *Description:* An application for ordering foods. Information was fetched real-time backed by MongoDB technologies.
  - *Technologies:* Built using Android Studio and backed by real-time NoSQL Realm by MongoDB, Inc.
  - Role: Working as a team leader.

# **TECHNOLOGIES AND TOOLS**

#### Skills:

- Programming Languages: Java

Database: MySQL

- Tools: IntelliJ, Source Tree, Github

Cloud Platform: AWSCl/CD Tools: Jenkins

# Knowledge and experiences:

Programming Languages: Python, Ruby

- Database: Postgres, MongoDB, iSeries

Tools: PyCharm, RubyMine, Linux, Mac, Windows

- Cloud Platform: Azure, AWS

### **EDUCATION**

**Udacity, Online** - Nanodegree Program

Data Engineer on AWS

FPT University - Bachelor Degree

Computer Software Engineering Bachelor's degree. 8.4/10

# **CERTIFICATES**

1. Certified Blockchain Practitioner - The SecOps Group

Issued: January 2023

2. Certified AppSec Practitioner - The SecOps Group

Issued: November 2022

3. AWS Certified Solutions Architect - Associate - Amazon

Issued: December 2022

4. AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner - Amazon

Issued: November 2022

5. Microsoft Certified Azure DevOps Engineer Expert - Microsoft

Issued: November 2022

6. Microsoft Certified: Azure Developer Associate - Microsoft

Issued: November 2022

7. Professional Scrum Master I - Scrum.org

Issued: November 2021

8. Microsoft 365 Certified: Fundamentals - Microsoft

Issued: October 2021

9. Microsoft Certified: Security, Compliance, and Identity Fundamentals - Microsoft

Issued: October 2021

10. CERTIFICATE OF ORAL PRESENTATION at The Sixth International Conference on Research in Intelligent and Computing in Engineering - RICE2021

Issued: June 2021

11. Microsoft Certified: Azure Al Fundamentals - Microsoft

Issued: June 2021

12. Microsoft Certified: Azure Data Fundamentals - Microsoft

Issued: June 2021

13. Microsoft Certified: Azure Fundamentals - Microsoft

Issued: June 2021

14. Project Management Principles and Practices Specialization - Coursera

Issued: November 2020

15. Startup Entrepreneurship Specialization - Coursera

Issued: Aug 2020